<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-04T08:03:36+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Kenan’s place</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SOMD Small Group</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/04/life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SOMD Small Group" /><published>2018-06-04T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/04/life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/04/life.html">&lt;p&gt;On the School of Ministry Development, we have two small groups of students and staff that meet each Thursday. Each student takes a turn leading the small group in a creative way. This is a great time to be involved in a smaller group, to learn about God in a new way or just process the week with others. It is also a time when we can step out in leading a small group in innovative ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/coffee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cup of coffee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy this time each Thursday and look forward to it. At small group I can hear what others know about the heart of God and we can help ech other bceomemore like Christ. We only have a few more weeks of small group here in Harpenden left. But we will also be doing small groups and group times in Cornwall together. Part of my role on outreach is to coordinate these times, I won’t be leading every time but will be making sure that someone is going to do it. I’m excited for the next phase of our journey as we go into Cornwall to love others as Christ loved us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On the School of Ministry Development, we have two small groups of students and staff that meet each Thursday. Each student takes a turn leading the small group in a creative way. This is a great time to be involved in a smaller group, to learn about God in a new way or just process the week with others. It is also a time when we can step out in leading a small group in innovative ways.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bible Study</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/04/bible-study.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bible Study" /><published>2018-06-04T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/04/bible-study</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/04/bible-study.html">&lt;p&gt;Check out my video on last week’s lectures
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Og1fB8LSIDg&quot;&gt;Bible Study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Check out my video on last week’s lectures Bible Study</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Crucial Conversations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/06/03/crucial-conversations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crucial Conversations" /><published>2018-06-03T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-03T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/06/03/crucial-conversations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/06/03/crucial-conversations.html">&lt;p&gt;The book, Crucial Conversations is written about having good conversations even if there are opposing opinions, strong emotions and high stakes involved. It is written by four authors, Kerry Patterson, Joseph Greeny, Ron McMillan and Al Switzler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the book they discuss how to take responsibility and have crucial conversations. First they expertly define what a crucial conversation is, “A discussion between two or more people where (1) stakes are high, (2) opinions vary, and (3) emotions run strong.” These conversations are very important, without them you may not be able to do well in your job, not be able to improve your organisation, lose relationships or even die. But our tendency is to avoid crucial conversations or handle them poorly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crucial conversations are not a one-sided monologue, it is a dialogue between at least two people. People need investment or meaning involved in decisions instead of being driven by fear, if they are being driven by fear then you miss out on their unique talents and abilities. In these situations of conflict, think, what do I really want? Then, “Work on me first, us second”. It is important to look at the end goal because often we get caught up in the little things that no parties actually care about. Make sure your own motives are good and not looking to hurt others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also need to be able to observe our crucial conversations and see our own and other people’s points of anger and learn to help guide through that. But we can make it safe to talk about almost anything because we can use mutual purpose and respect to show our real motives for others. These points of anger for ourselves our painful but if we can recognise them we can move past into something better for both ourselves and our teams. In the next section of the book we look at how to share our stories (or paths) and move into a place of understanding each other. Conversely, we also learn how to really listen to other people’s stories, even through high emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all of this doesn’t really mean much if we don’t make a decision and more forward into action as a team. The book discusses four different types of decision making: Command (making a decision with no involvment whatsover), Consult (hearing other opinions and then making a decision), Vote or Consensus. These four decision making types all have their place and must be used appropriately, using them inappropriately will lead to anger and fires. The book ends with many examples of different crucial conversation stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book really made a huge lasting impact on my life and I don’t think I will ever be quite the same. The biggest huge impact that it had was just showing me that I can have crucial conversations well and it doesn’t have to be a bad thing. In my life I will defintely use these concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A concept that I will use a lot is STATE (to share your path or story):&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share your facts. Start with the least controversial, most persuasive elemeents from your path toAction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell your story. Explain what you’re beginning to conclude.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask for others’ paths. Encourage others to share both their facts and their storeis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk tentatively. State your story as a story - don’t disguise it as a fact.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encourage testing. Make it safe for others to express differing or even opposing views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point of impact for me personally is the chapter on moving to action, turing crucial conversations into action and results, to not just be in dialogue but to actually move forward was great encouragement and help for me. As well as the quote in the book by Ouida, “I have known a thousand scamps; but I never met one who considered himself so. Self-knowledge isn’t so common.” Oh if we would move past the point of just looking towards ourselves and our own needs and consider the needs of others, without trying to take responsibility for others but to them instead. Read the book, Crucial Conversations today please, you can find it in your local bookstore.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The book, Crucial Conversations is written about having good conversations even if there are opposing opinions, strong emotions and high stakes involved. It is written by four authors, Kerry Patterson, Joseph Greeny, Ron McMillan and Al Switzler.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Roommate - Nat</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/21/my-roommate-nat.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Roommate - Nat" /><published>2018-05-21T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-21T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/21/my-roommate-nat</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/21/my-roommate-nat.html">&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to tell you a little bit about my roommate and friend, Nat. His real name is Nathaniel, aka Nat, aka Nate-Dog (but I never hear anyone call him that). Nat is an English man from the southern part of the country, Chestershire, it’s actually part of the dukedom of the Duke and Duchess of Sussex. There is a also a famous cathedral in the city of Chestershire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/nat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nat in Chesham&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first met Nat after he got back from staffing a DTS outreach, I got to know him just a little before he left on holiday. But when he came back we started the School of Ministry Development together and have gotten to know him much better since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room in which we live is called The Kenat House and we only have six rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No drugs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No smoking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes to smelling good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes to cleanliness (which is next to godliness)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes to &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; peeing the bed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nat is a very chilled person who takes things day by day. He’s learning to play guiitar and loves reading the Bible and books about the Bible. Nat is a skilled drummer and loves God, ladies, he’s single, think about it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today I’d like to tell you a little bit about my roommate and friend, Nat. His real name is Nathaniel, aka Nat, aka Nate-Dog (but I never hear anyone call him that). Nat is an English man from the southern part of the country, Chestershire, it’s actually part of the dukedom of the Duke and Duchess of Sussex. There is a also a famous cathedral in the city of Chestershire.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christ-like Leadership</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/21/christ-like-leadership.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christ-like Leadership" /><published>2018-05-21T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-21T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/21/christ-like-leadership</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/21/christ-like-leadership.html">&lt;p&gt;This past week we had the pleasure of having Judy Orred teaching our School of Ministry Development class on the topic of Christ-like Leadership. I really enjoyed her teaching and how she explored different topics with us, helping us grow, and didn’t come with material that she had to get through. Judy Orred is from YWAM Kona and she has a lot of experience in leadership, some of my favourite times were hearing her speak about what she has done in the past and learned from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked a lot about truth in the class and its weight. Truth demands a response, to be loyal or not. God tells us what we need to hear and not more because we need proper foundations in our life to handle that truth properly, for instance, the foundation of knowing your identity in the Father.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/coast.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coast in England, not the only coast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I really liked was when she talked about fearing God instead of fearing people. We can have great confidence in a leader who fears God more than most, as Nehemiah did, “I gave the responsibility of governing Jerusalem to my brother Hanani, along with Hananiah, the commander of the fortress, for he was a faithful man who feared God more than most.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This past week we had the pleasure of having Judy Orred teaching our School of Ministry Development class on the topic of Christ-like Leadership. I really enjoyed her teaching and how she explored different topics with us, helping us grow, and didn’t come with material that she had to get through. Judy Orred is from YWAM Kona and she has a lot of experience in leadership, some of my favourite times were hearing her speak about what she has done in the past and learned from.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebration of Discipline</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/05/17/celebration-of-discipline.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebration of Discipline" /><published>2018-05-17T20:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-17T20:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/05/17/celebration-of-discipline</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/05/17/celebration-of-discipline.html">&lt;p&gt;Celebration of Discipline is a lovely book which focuses on practical ways to grow spiritually in your life with God. It calls us from the shallow into deep spiritual waters. The book looks at twelve classic spiritual disciplines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meditation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prayer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fasting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Study&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplicity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solitude&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confession&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worship&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each of these disciplines, the author Richard Foster examines the history of the discipline, its benefits, his personal experience and how to grow in the discipline over time. These disciplines are so important because they are practical building blocks of how to grow in relationship with Father God, not religous rites. Richard Foster also dicusses the potential danger or controversies of the discipline. At the end of each discipline chapter, he includes questions for reflection and provides sources for plenty of supplemental reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book impacted me in that it challenged me to step from the superficial into deep waters. I am starting to practice these disciplines and I am finding much delight in the intimacy with God that I didn’t have before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my highlights was the discipline of meditation, which is simply slowing down and taking time to really conteplate. There isn’t a special way to do it, aside from just deciding to start. I find this meditation very helpful, along with prayer, in focusing on the things that are important and silencing what is not important. Reading about different forms of meditation was also very interesting, for instance, meditating on Scripture, past events, God’s creations and the events of our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another was the discipline of fasting, I haven’t explored fasting very much at all, I had wondered about what the practical steps are. Celebration of Discipline really helped by answering questions I had: how long do fasts last? what are the different kinds of fasts? How does it feel to be on a fast? Why should you fast? Is fasting a commandment? Thank you Richard Foster! I love this quote, “Fasting reminds us that we are sustained: ‘by every word that proceeds from the mouth of God’ (Matthew 4:4). Food does not sustain us; God sustains us. In Christ, ‘All things hold together’ (Colossians 1:17). Therefore, in experiences of fasting we are not so much abstaining from food as we are feasting on the word of God. Fasting is feasting!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discipline of confession was quite challenging for me, what a step! “The confession of evil works in the first beginning of good works.” - Augustine of Hippo. Richard Foster focuses on the authority we’ve been given as believers to hear each other’s sins and forgive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chapter on the discipline of guidance was a special blessing. What a joy it is to find counsel in many believers! I think it is a tendency to want to make decisions on my own and not involve others. Even though it is my responsibility, my decisions still affect others. Through the body of Christ, we can see more of the Father’s heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked forward to the discipline of celebration as I neared the end of Celebration of Discipline. As we were reminded during our recent YWAM UK and Ireland gathering, seriousness is not a fruit of the Spirit, but joy is. Celebration is something to be celebrated, Jesus had a reputation for his celebrations. We can grow closer to God through celebrating his goodness together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book impacted me and will continue to impact me and by extension, ministries, in how I relate to God and others. I really don’t look at life and ministry as being two different things, our school should really be called School of Development, in my opinion. Two thirds of these disciplines are directly related to others, and all can be applied to any believers I interact with. The challenge now is to walk out these principles in my life, not in fa way that focuses on actions but on relationship with Father and others. May he help me as I continue to walk this path with excellence and empower others to be stronger in their walks and abilities. “We look into the face of God until we ache with bliss, as Frank Laubach witnessed, ‘I know what it means to be “God-intoxicated”’”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Celebration of Discipline is a lovely book which focuses on practical ways to grow spiritually in your life with God. It calls us from the shallow into deep spiritual waters. The book looks at twelve classic spiritual disciplines:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Evangelism and Missions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/14/evangelism-and-missions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Evangelism and Missions" /><published>2018-05-14T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-14T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/14/evangelism-and-missions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/14/evangelism-and-missions.html">&lt;p&gt;This past week we had two speakers in our School of Ministry Development, I enjoyed hearing from both speakers. They both helped us in preparing for outreach in both theory and practical ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/globe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A globe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laurence Singlehurst spoke on evangelism the first two days, he gave us personal stories as well as deeper ideas behind evangelism. He told us the story of Christianity in Britain since its beginning, about the different historical events and revivals in the land throughout the centuries. One of my big takeaways was that in outreach, to know that you may be preparing the ground to make it fertile soil, as in the parable of the seeds. Some groups of people in the world don’t even know that God is good, this is something that we can show to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big takeaway I had from Laurence’s teaching, which is related, is that we need to make sure that people know what they are doing when they accept Christ. “Other seeds fell on shallow soil with underlying rock. The seeds sprouted quickly because the soil was shallow. But the plants soon wilted under the hot sun, and since they didn’t have deep roots, they died.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much more and more depth but it is hard to put into words on this blog, this teaching will be very hel;pful for outreach and for future ministry.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This past week we had two speakers in our School of Ministry Development, I enjoyed hearing from both speakers. They both helped us in preparing for outreach in both theory and practical ideas.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alpha</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/14/alpha.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alpha" /><published>2018-05-14T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-14T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/14/alpha</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/14/alpha.html">&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, a study was created to educate people, especially non-believers, on what Christians and the Bible are about. This is called Alpha, you might have heard of it, especiallyh if you are from the UK. This is a very cool tool which really goes into the basics of the Christian faith and invites people to think about the Gospel message. You can see more &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our School of Ministry Development, we have started Alpha groups for two age groups of kids from YWAM Harpenden. We start with a game and then watch the youth Alpha video. During the video there are three questions to create discussion in our groups. It is a great time, the kids really engage and we have good conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/kid-with-bible.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kid reading a BIble&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy doing Alpha with these kids and my friend Letícia. It’s cool to get to know the kids from YWAM Harpenden better. This is important to ground these kids in biblical truth and get them thinking about what Father is like. Be praying for us as we continue to walk with these kids in Alpha and give them what they will need in the future. See you next week with another story!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Several years ago, a study was created to educate people, especially non-believers, on what Christians and the Bible are about. This is called Alpha, you might have heard of it, especiallyh if you are from the UK. This is a very cool tool which really goes into the basics of the Christian faith and invites people to think about the Gospel message. You can see more here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Self-Leadership</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/08/self-leadership.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-Leadership" /><published>2018-05-08T08:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-08T08:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/08/self-leadership</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/08/self-leadership.html">&lt;p&gt;Last week Michael Green spoke to our class on the topic of self-leadership, it’s all about living intentionally and not accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/walking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the subjects that really impacted me was the Five Gears, which are different states that you can be at throughout each day. 5th gear is focus mode, when you are working on one thing with all of your concentration. 4th gear is task mode when you are working on many different things at once. 3rd gear is social mode, when you are being around people casually. 2nd gear is connect mode when you are connecting with people on a deeper level. 1st gear is recharge mode when you are alone and doing what you need to be charged for the other gears. There is also reverse which is a responsive mode when you are going back and correcting for mistakes. These are significant because some gears are easier for others and some gears we are not as good at doing in a healthy way. It is important to make sure that you are in the correct gear, for instance, when we are eating dinner together in the dining hall, it is not a good time to be in 4th gear, working on tasks instead of socialising or connecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael also talked about the different voices that people have on a team, while some may be a loud, pioneering voice, we need to take time to hear those who will be quieter when decisions are being made. On our team we need to take time to hear from each of us and use our gifts to benefit others and not tear them down.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last week Michael Green spoke to our class on the topic of self-leadership, it’s all about living intentionally and not accidentally.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WISE Gathering</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/08/wise-gathering.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WISE Gathering" /><published>2018-05-08T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-08T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/08/wise-gathering</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/08/wise-gathering.html">&lt;p&gt;As we were cleaning up on Monday after the WISE (Wales, Ireland, Scotland, England) Gathering this past weekend, we were all engaged in various tasks. We had to clear lots of equipment and clean many different spaces around the Oval. I walked from the Clock Building over towards the marquee (a big tent), where there were others gathered waiting for jobs to do. As I approached, I saw that Makayla was standing between me and the others. She saw me walking in her general direction and what she did next was unexpected. Makayla raised her right arm and extended her hand to me, I could tell that she seemed tired and probably needed a boost. But at the same time, I needed to get to where I was going so that we could finish up the work for the day. Then, an idea struck me, I continued to walk her way, slightly to the left of her, but with even greater speed. As I got closer, I raised my right arm as well, grabbed her hand, let go and both of us were propelled in the opposite direction. What a strange story, it all happened in about fifteen seconds. I look at it as a physical example of how our class can work together to be propelled into God’s calling for us, even if we aren’t going in the same direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/hand.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An open hand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As we were cleaning up on Monday after the WISE (Wales, Ireland, Scotland, England) Gathering this past weekend, we were all engaged in various tasks. We had to clear lots of equipment and clean many different spaces around the Oval. I walked from the Clock Building over towards the marquee (a big tent), where there were others gathered waiting for jobs to do. As I approached, I saw that Makayla was standing between me and the others. She saw me walking in her general direction and what she did next was unexpected. Makayla raised her right arm and extended her hand to me, I could tell that she seemed tired and probably needed a boost. But at the same time, I needed to get to where I was going so that we could finish up the work for the day. Then, an idea struck me, I continued to walk her way, slightly to the left of her, but with even greater speed. As I got closer, I raised my right arm as well, grabbed her hand, let go and both of us were propelled in the opposite direction. What a strange story, it all happened in about fifteen seconds. I look at it as a physical example of how our class can work together to be propelled into God’s calling for us, even if we aren’t going in the same direction.</summary></entry></feed>