<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-25T08:25:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Kenan’s place</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The King’s Lodge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/25/the-kings-lodge.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The King's Lodge" /><published>2018-06-25T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-25T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/25/the-kings-lodge</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/25/the-kings-lodge.html">&lt;p&gt;Last Sunday, five of us from the campus went on a road trip to The King’s Lodge to visit two of our friends who are doing a Bible school there. We took a rental car over there, only about a hour and a half drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/kings.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The King's Lodge&quot; /&gt;
Photo © Mat Fascione (cc-by-sa/2.0)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The King’s Lodge is a beautiful YWAM location, it is out in the peaceful country. The lodge is two large buildings, I believe, with several stories. In the bottom centre is a beautiful lounge and cafe area, a worship space and dining hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all had a wonderful time visiting for a few hours and seeing what life is like for our friends doing school there. I even got a painting out of the trip. I won’t say who, but one of us deposited prawns in the bin of their cafe. This caused the whole area to stink for a while until someone traced the scent. Ha ha, I feel bad for them but I also appreciate the funny story that we can tell in future years. Until next time, God bless you all, God bless you Mary A., I enjoyed our breakfast on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last Sunday, five of us from the campus went on a road trip to The King’s Lodge to visit two of our friends who are doing a Bible school there. We took a rental car over there, only about a hour and a half drive.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Inductive Bible Study</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/25/inductive-bible-study.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inductive Bible Study" /><published>2018-06-25T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-25T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/25/inductive-bible-study</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/25/inductive-bible-study.html">&lt;p&gt;Last week we had lectures on a couple of different topics, including how to do an Inductive Bible Study. Inductive Bible Study an approach of studying the Bible which looks at what the Bible says, asking lots of questions, and helping you apply what you learn. Contrast with deductive Bible study which is not neccesarily bad but approaches the Bible with a topic or question to be answered, making it easy to miss things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step of Inductive Bible Study is Observation, asking the question, “what is written in the text?”, without asking what it means, drawing conclusions, comparing it with other passages, etc. For this you can use coloured pencils to make it easy to understand the text that you are looking at. During Observation you can ask what words are used, who is mentioned, what locations are mentioned, where it is taking placing and who the author and reciepient is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/bible.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bible with colouring&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next is Interpretation which asks, “What did it mean to the original reader?”, not asking what it means to you or society today. This requires a lot of research to understand the historical context of the author and reciepient, using a lot of Bible resources, but it is very helpful because it provides information that we just wouldn’t see by reading the text. For example, the churches that Paul wrote to were in very different cities, and he wrote to different kinds of people, this affected what he wrote because those letters were written to specific groups of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Application is asking, “What does it mean to me?”. This is the goal of the inductive method, if you don’t do this step then you might as well not start at all because you just get a lot of knowledge but with no change in your life. In this step we are finding timeless truths, meaning, truths that were applicable to the original reader/hearer and to me and for everyone across all times and all cultures. In this step we ask, what the original text means to me, how can I apply it, what the original text means to my time in history, my community and my church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so glad that I heard this teaching, as Inductive Bible Study has been something I’ve heard about frequently but didn’t know how to actually do it. I will defintely be implementing this into my Bible study times.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last week we had lectures on a couple of different topics, including how to do an Inductive Bible Study. Inductive Bible Study an approach of studying the Bible which looks at what the Bible says, asking lots of questions, and helping you apply what you learn. Contrast with deductive Bible study which is not neccesarily bad but approaches the Bible with a topic or question to be answered, making it easy to miss things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Report - How to Lead When You’re Not in Charge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/06/22/how-to-lead.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Report - How to Lead When You're Not in Charge" /><published>2018-06-22T15:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T15:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/06/22/how-to-lead</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/06/22/how-to-lead.html">&lt;p&gt;How to Lead When You’re Not in Charge is a book written by Clay Scroggins, I chose to read this book as the last book on my School of Ministry Development. The book discusses the importance of leading with influence and relatinships, instead of title, position, power or money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Clay Scroggins goes over why using your position often to lead from is a dangerous slope and not a mark of a good leader. It is also important to be yourself and not try to lead like someone that you’re not. God has placed the mandate to subdue deep within us, but it is not what we may think of as crushing things beneath us, it is helping them grow. Genesis 1:28 says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Then God blessed them and said, “Be fruitful and multiply. Fill the earth and govern it. Reign over the fish in the sea, the birds in the sky, and all the animals that scurry along the ground.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Jesus elborates on this in teaching his disciples in Matthew 20:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You know that the rulers in this world lord it over their people, and officials flaunt their authority over those under them. But among you it will be different. Whoever wants to be a leader among you must be your servant, and whoever wants to be first among you must become your slave. For even the Son of Man came not to be served but to serve others and to give his life as a ransom for many.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Clay Scroggins goes into talking about the importance of leading yourself before you lead anyone else, and how to do that. If you can’t lead yourself well, can you lead anyone else? This includes choosing posititivity in your attitude, thinking critically and rejecting passivity. He finishes the book with a section on how to start being a leader before you ever have position and to grow in your influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were serveral parts of this book that really stood out to me, the first was in the foreward by Andy Stanley:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Great leaders leverage influence and relationships over title and poisition. When a leader is left with nothing to leverage other than title and position, the end is near. The best leaders lead like they’re not in charge, even when they are. The best leaders become the leaders by mastering the art of leading when you’re not in charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a great statement, that the best leaders lead like they’re not in charge. “When people have to tell you that they’re in charge in order for you to follow, you know instinctively that something has gone desparately wrong.” The author talks about practice as “pulling the gun”. This way of leading does not produce lasting results, people will eventually leave. This is also talked about in the book, The Five Levels of Leadership by John Maxwell, another great book which expounds on this topic. In the end, you want people to want to follow you, not forced to because of a threat. This is something that we have to operate with in YWAM because everyone is a volunteer, you can’t hold the threat of losing a salary when we don’t have it at all through the organisation itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point is that we have the ability to lead in doing things that no one else wants to do. We need to have active minds and hearts to go from doing what we’re told to do, to also finding what we are going to do, and do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clay Scroggins focuses on the importance of leading yourself well, before you are leading anyone else. I will expand on this below but for now, I was struck by the passage of Scripture that he referenced in Luke:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you are faithful in little things, you will be faithful in large ones. But if you are dishonest in little things, you won’t be honest with greater responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A way to be accountable to leading yourself well is to have deadlines where others are expecting you to have completed something and you just have to do it and lead yourself well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final highlight I will mention is that it is important not to be passive, you have a voice and need to speak up when something needs to change and you have a plan to change it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that I keep thinking of is the importance of self-leadership, I’ve known this before of course but it feels more real now. It’s a bit of a joke that I’m leading the IT department here at YWAM Harpenden, because I’m also the only one in the IT department here at YWAM Harpenden. Jason was my leader before he left but he never told me what to do, other than that I needed to decide what I was going to spend my time on. Through our collaboration we have done so much and took care of real needs without anyone dictating what we were to do each day. So even though I’m the only one, I am leading the IT department, I’m leading myself in what I choose to do each day, the attitude I have, and the culture that I create.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How to Lead When You’re Not in Charge is a book written by Clay Scroggins, I chose to read this book as the last book on my School of Ministry Development. The book discusses the importance of leading with influence and relatinships, instead of title, position, power or money.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer Fun Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/20/summer-fun-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer Fun Day" /><published>2018-06-20T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-20T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/20/summer-fun-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/20/summer-fun-day.html">&lt;p&gt;This past Saturday we hosted an event here at the Oval called Summer Fun Day. This is an annual event where we invite families from Harpenden to come and eat, play games and other cool things. The local fire brigade even came and showed the truck to the kids!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I helped with the Fun Run and the Oval Run. The Fun Run is a mile long run for kids and families, it was really cool to see everyone getting out there and partaking in this fun event. The Oval Run is a five mile long run for adults which was quite awesome to see. How fast they run! Cesar and I gave the runners food and drink, like bananas, hob nobs, apple slices, and water When I saw them run, I thought, “I wish I could run like that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/runner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A runner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the next time that the Summer Fun Day somes along, I will look forward to participating. Not only did it have all of this, but we also had Brazillian Barbeque: steak, chips, nachos and some assorted fruits. It was quite delicious, but the time in the community was even better, just seeing everyone working together and bringing joy to the families around Harpenden.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This past Saturday we hosted an event here at the Oval called Summer Fun Day. This is an annual event where we invite families from Harpenden to come and eat, play games and other cool things. The local fire brigade even came and showed the truck to the kids!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fundraising</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/11/fundraising.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fundraising" /><published>2018-06-11T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-11T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/11/fundraising</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/11/fundraising.html">&lt;p&gt;Last week, Laura Mudd taught on fundraising in our School of Ministry Devlopment class. This was such a powerful teaching for me because it really showed me more of the spiritual elements behind fundraising and what I can do to communicate my vision better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can tend to dread fundraising and think of it as a neccesary evil to be able to be a missionary, but the truth is that it is good to be able to be supported by others. It builds relationships, accountability and faith. The structure that Youth With A Mission is wouldn’t work without relying on God for our finances personally and not receiving a salary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big takeaway is that fundraising is not about us, or money, it’s about God’s vision for each of our lives. When I speak to someone about what I am doing in England, I can be bold about what God has called me to do, what support I need to see it happen and ask for someone to be a part of the vision, to send young people out into the nations and all parts of society with the Good News.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/mountains.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mountains&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another challenge that I had was to keep a proper budget, which I have now started. It was one of those things that I just overlooked in moving here but it really is important. I’m actually good at working with a budget and keeping financial records but I had not applied that to my own life before. I will keep an accurate ledger just as if it was someone else’s money that I was working with, because it is God’s money, not mine anyways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could keep writing about this week but I’m going to stop here for sake of time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last week, Laura Mudd taught on fundraising in our School of Ministry Devlopment class. This was such a powerful teaching for me because it really showed me more of the spiritual elements behind fundraising and what I can do to communicate my vision better.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boundaries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/11/boundaries.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boundaries" /><published>2018-06-11T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-11T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/11/boundaries</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/11/boundaries.html">&lt;p&gt;The past couple of weeks I have really felt the need to make some adjustments to how I spend my time. Up until School of Ministry Devlopment I was pretty balanced but now I am attending the school and taking more responsibilities in IT at the same time as I will soon be the only person in IT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This calls for some reshaping of my boundaries on my time, both in my work and self. What this means for work is using Do Not Disturb on my phone even more, and not understanding what is an IT emergency and what can actually wait. For myself, it means taking real rest like walking, watching the sunset over the English hills or talking with friends, instead of working every minute of the weekdays and watching YouTube all of the weekend. It’s about having realistic expectations of what I am capable of doing and thinking about the big picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/windmill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Countryside&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been reading Boundaries by Henry Cloud and John Townsend for the second time and was reminded of the importance of making boundaries in Christian fellowship, to not make them in a vacuum. I am now getting some help with being kept accountable for the boundaries I set, in order for me to live an abundant life!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The past couple of weeks I have really felt the need to make some adjustments to how I spend my time. Up until School of Ministry Devlopment I was pretty balanced but now I am attending the school and taking more responsibilities in IT at the same time as I will soon be the only person in IT.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SOMD Small Group</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/04/life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SOMD Small Group" /><published>2018-06-04T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/04/life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/06/04/life.html">&lt;p&gt;On the School of Ministry Development, we have two small groups of students and staff that meet each Thursday. Each student takes a turn leading the small group in a creative way. This is a great time to be involved in a smaller group, to learn about God in a new way or just process the week with others. It is also a time when we can step out in leading a small group in innovative ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/coffee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cup of coffee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy this time each Thursday and look forward to it. At small group I can hear what others know about the heart of God and we can help ech other bceomemore like Christ. We only have a few more weeks of small group here in Harpenden left. But we will also be doing small groups and group times in Cornwall together. Part of my role on outreach is to coordinate these times, I won’t be leading every time but will be making sure that someone is going to do it. I’m excited for the next phase of our journey as we go into Cornwall to love others as Christ loved us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On the School of Ministry Development, we have two small groups of students and staff that meet each Thursday. Each student takes a turn leading the small group in a creative way. This is a great time to be involved in a smaller group, to learn about God in a new way or just process the week with others. It is also a time when we can step out in leading a small group in innovative ways.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bible Study</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/04/bible-study.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bible Study" /><published>2018-06-04T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-04T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/04/bible-study</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/06/04/bible-study.html">&lt;p&gt;Check out my video on last week’s lectures
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Og1fB8LSIDg&quot;&gt;Bible Study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Check out my video on last week’s lectures Bible Study</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Crucial Conversations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/06/03/crucial-conversations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crucial Conversations" /><published>2018-06-03T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-03T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/06/03/crucial-conversations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/06/03/crucial-conversations.html">&lt;p&gt;The book, Crucial Conversations is written about having good conversations even if there are opposing opinions, strong emotions and high stakes involved. It is written by four authors, Kerry Patterson, Joseph Greeny, Ron McMillan and Al Switzler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the book they discuss how to take responsibility and have crucial conversations. First they expertly define what a crucial conversation is, “A discussion between two or more people where (1) stakes are high, (2) opinions vary, and (3) emotions run strong.” These conversations are very important, without them you may not be able to do well in your job, not be able to improve your organisation, lose relationships or even die. But our tendency is to avoid crucial conversations or handle them poorly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crucial conversations are not a one-sided monologue, it is a dialogue between at least two people. People need investment or meaning involved in decisions instead of being driven by fear, if they are being driven by fear then you miss out on their unique talents and abilities. In these situations of conflict, think, what do I really want? Then, “Work on me first, us second”. It is important to look at the end goal because often we get caught up in the little things that no parties actually care about. Make sure your own motives are good and not looking to hurt others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also need to be able to observe our crucial conversations and see our own and other people’s points of anger and learn to help guide through that. But we can make it safe to talk about almost anything because we can use mutual purpose and respect to show our real motives for others. These points of anger for ourselves our painful but if we can recognise them we can move past into something better for both ourselves and our teams. In the next section of the book we look at how to share our stories (or paths) and move into a place of understanding each other. Conversely, we also learn how to really listen to other people’s stories, even through high emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all of this doesn’t really mean much if we don’t make a decision and more forward into action as a team. The book discusses four different types of decision making: Command (making a decision with no involvment whatsover), Consult (hearing other opinions and then making a decision), Vote or Consensus. These four decision making types all have their place and must be used appropriately, using them inappropriately will lead to anger and fires. The book ends with many examples of different crucial conversation stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book really made a huge lasting impact on my life and I don’t think I will ever be quite the same. The biggest huge impact that it had was just showing me that I can have crucial conversations well and it doesn’t have to be a bad thing. In my life I will defintely use these concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A concept that I will use a lot is STATE (to share your path or story):&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share your facts. Start with the least controversial, most persuasive elemeents from your path toAction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell your story. Explain what you’re beginning to conclude.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask for others’ paths. Encourage others to share both their facts and their storeis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk tentatively. State your story as a story - don’t disguise it as a fact.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encourage testing. Make it safe for others to express differing or even opposing views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point of impact for me personally is the chapter on moving to action, turing crucial conversations into action and results, to not just be in dialogue but to actually move forward was great encouragement and help for me. As well as the quote in the book by Ouida, “I have known a thousand scamps; but I never met one who considered himself so. Self-knowledge isn’t so common.” Oh if we would move past the point of just looking towards ourselves and our own needs and consider the needs of others, without trying to take responsibility for others but to them instead. Read the book, Crucial Conversations today please, you can find it in your local bookstore.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The book, Crucial Conversations is written about having good conversations even if there are opposing opinions, strong emotions and high stakes involved. It is written by four authors, Kerry Patterson, Joseph Greeny, Ron McMillan and Al Switzler.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Roommate - Nat</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/21/my-roommate-nat.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Roommate - Nat" /><published>2018-05-21T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-21T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/21/my-roommate-nat</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/21/my-roommate-nat.html">&lt;p&gt;Today I’d like to tell you a little bit about my roommate and friend, Nat. His real name is Nathaniel, aka Nat, aka Nate-Dog (but I never hear anyone call him that). Nat is an English man from the southern part of the country, Chestershire, it’s actually part of the dukedom of the Duke and Duchess of Sussex. There is a also a famous cathedral in the city of Chestershire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/nat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nat in Chesham&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first met Nat after he got back from staffing a DTS outreach, I got to know him just a little before he left on holiday. But when he came back we started the School of Ministry Development together and have gotten to know him much better since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room in which we live is called The Kenat House and we only have six rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No drugs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No smoking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes to smelling good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes to cleanliness (which is next to godliness)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes to &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; peeing the bed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nat is a very chilled person who takes things day by day. He’s learning to play guiitar and loves reading the Bible and books about the Bible. Nat is a skilled drummer and loves God, ladies, he’s single, think about it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today I’d like to tell you a little bit about my roommate and friend, Nat. His real name is Nathaniel, aka Nat, aka Nate-Dog (but I never hear anyone call him that). Nat is an English man from the southern part of the country, Chestershire, it’s actually part of the dukedom of the Duke and Duchess of Sussex. There is a also a famous cathedral in the city of Chestershire.</summary></entry></feed>