<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-17T23:00:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Kenan’s place</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Celebration of Discipline</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/05/17/celebration-of-discipline.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebration of Discipline" /><published>2018-05-17T20:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-17T20:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/05/17/celebration-of-discipline</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/05/17/celebration-of-discipline.html">&lt;p&gt;Celebration of Discipline is a lovely book which focuses on practical ways to grow spiritually in your life with God. It calls us from the shallow into deep spiritual waters. The book looks at twelve classic spiritual disciplines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meditation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prayer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fasting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Study&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simplicity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solitude&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confession&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worship&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each of these disciplines, the author Richard Foster examines the history of the discipline, its benefits, his personal experience and how to grow in the discipline over time. These disciplines are so important because they are practical building blocks of how to grow in relationship with Father God, not religous rites. Richard Foster also dicusses the potential danger or controversies of the discipline. At the end of each discipline chapter, he includes questions for reflection and provides sources for plenty of supplemental reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book impacted me in that it challenged me to step from the superficial into deep waters. I am starting to practice these disciplines and I am finding much delight in the intimacy with God that I didn’t have before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my highlights was the discipline of meditation, which is simply slowing down and taking time to really conteplate. There isn’t a special way to do it, aside from just deciding to start. I find this meditation very helpful, along with prayer, in focusing on the things that are important and silencing what is not important. Reading about different forms of meditation was also very interesting, for instance, meditating on Scripture, past events, God’s creations and the events of our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another was the discipline of fasting, I haven’t explored fasting very much at all, I had wondered about what the practical steps are. Celebration of Discipline really helped by answering questions I had: how long do fasts last? what are the different kinds of fasts? How does it feel to be on a fast? Why should you fast? Is fasting a commandment? Thank you Richard Foster! I love this quote, “Fasting reminds us that we are sustained: ‘by every word that proceeds from the mouth of God’ (Matthew 4:4). Food does not sustain us; God sustains us. In Christ, ‘All things hold together’ (Colossians 1:17). Therefore, in experiences of fasting we are not so much abstaining from food as we are feasting on the word of God. Fasting is feasting!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discipline of confession was quite challenging for me, what a step! “The confession of evil works in the first beginning of good works.” - Augustine of Hippo. Richard Foster focuses on the authority we’ve been given as believers to hear each other’s sins and forgive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chapter on the discipline of guidance was a special blessing. What a joy it is to find counsel in many believers! I think it is a tendency to want to make decisions on my own and not involve others. Even though it is my responsibility, my decisions still affect others. Through the body of Christ, we can see more of the Father’s heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked forward to the discipline of celebration as I neared the end of Celebration of Discipline. As we were reminded during our recent YWAM UK and Ireland gathering, seriousness is not a fruit of the Spirit, but joy is. Celebration is something to be celebrated, Jesus had a reputation for his celebrations. We can grow closer to God through celebrating his goodness together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book impacted me and will continue to impact me and by extension, ministries, in how I relate to God and others. I really don’t look at life and ministry as being two different things, our school should really be called School of Development, in my opinion. Two thirds of these disciplines are directly related to others, and all can be applied to any believers I interact with. The challenge now is to walk out these principles in my life, not in fa way that focuses on actions but on relationship with Father and others. May he help me as I continue to walk this path with excellence and empower others to be stronger in their walks and abilities. “We look into the face of God until we ache with bliss, as Frank Laubach witnessed, ‘I know what it means to be “God-intoxicated”’”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Celebration of Discipline is a lovely book which focuses on practical ways to grow spiritually in your life with God. It calls us from the shallow into deep spiritual waters. The book looks at twelve classic spiritual disciplines:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Evangelism and Missions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/14/evangelism-and-missions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Evangelism and Missions" /><published>2018-05-14T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-14T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/14/evangelism-and-missions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/14/evangelism-and-missions.html">&lt;p&gt;This past week we had two speakers in our School of Ministry Development, I enjoyed hearing from both speakers. They both helped us in preparing for outreach in both theory and practical ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/globe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A globe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laurence Singlehurst spoke on evangelism the first two days, he gave us personal stories as well as deeper ideas behind evangelism. He told us the story of Christianity in Britain since its beginning, about the different historical events and revivals in the land throughout the centuries. One of my big takeaways was that in outreach, to know that you may be preparing the ground to make it fertile soil, as in the parable of the seeds. Some groups of people in the world don’t even know that God is good, this is something that we can show to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big takeaway I had from Laurence’s teaching, which is related, is that we need to make sure that people know what they are doing when they accept Christ. “Other seeds fell on shallow soil with underlying rock. The seeds sprouted quickly because the soil was shallow. But the plants soon wilted under the hot sun, and since they didn’t have deep roots, they died.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much more and more depth but it is hard to put into words on this blog, this teaching will be very hel;pful for outreach and for future ministry.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This past week we had two speakers in our School of Ministry Development, I enjoyed hearing from both speakers. They both helped us in preparing for outreach in both theory and practical ideas.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alpha</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/14/alpha.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alpha" /><published>2018-05-14T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-14T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/14/alpha</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/14/alpha.html">&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, a study was created to educate people, especially non-believers, on what Christians and the Bible are about. This is called Alpha, you might have heard of it, especiallyh if you are from the UK. This is a very cool tool which really goes into the basics of the Christian faith and invites people to think about the Gospel message. You can see more &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our School of Ministry Development, we have started Alpha groups for two age groups of kids from YWAM Harpenden. We start with a game and then watch the youth Alpha video. During the video there are three questions to create discussion in our groups. It is a great time, the kids really engage and we have good conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/kid-with-bible.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kid reading a BIble&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy doing Alpha with these kids and my friend Letícia. It’s cool to get to know the kids from YWAM Harpenden better. This is important to ground these kids in biblical truth and get them thinking about what Father is like. Be praying for us as we continue to walk with these kids in Alpha and give them what they will need in the future. See you next week with another story!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Several years ago, a study was created to educate people, especially non-believers, on what Christians and the Bible are about. This is called Alpha, you might have heard of it, especiallyh if you are from the UK. This is a very cool tool which really goes into the basics of the Christian faith and invites people to think about the Gospel message. You can see more here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Self-Leadership</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/08/self-leadership.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-Leadership" /><published>2018-05-08T08:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-08T08:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/08/self-leadership</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/05/08/self-leadership.html">&lt;p&gt;Last week Michael Green spoke to our class on the topic of self-leadership, it’s all about living intentionally and not accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/walking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the subjects that really impacted me was the Five Gears, which are different states that you can be at throughout each day. 5th gear is focus mode, when you are working on one thing with all of your concentration. 4th gear is task mode when you are working on many different things at once. 3rd gear is social mode, when you are being around people casually. 2nd gear is connect mode when you are connecting with people on a deeper level. 1st gear is recharge mode when you are alone and doing what you need to be charged for the other gears. There is also reverse which is a responsive mode when you are going back and correcting for mistakes. These are significant because some gears are easier for others and some gears we are not as good at doing in a healthy way. It is important to make sure that you are in the correct gear, for instance, when we are eating dinner together in the dining hall, it is not a good time to be in 4th gear, working on tasks instead of socialising or connecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael also talked about the different voices that people have on a team, while some may be a loud, pioneering voice, we need to take time to hear those who will be quieter when decisions are being made. On our team we need to take time to hear from each of us and use our gifts to benefit others and not tear them down.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last week Michael Green spoke to our class on the topic of self-leadership, it’s all about living intentionally and not accidentally.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WISE Gathering</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/08/wise-gathering.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WISE Gathering" /><published>2018-05-08T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-08T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/08/wise-gathering</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/05/08/wise-gathering.html">&lt;p&gt;As we were cleaning up on Monday after the WISE (Wales, Ireland, Scotland, England) Gathering this past weekend, we were all engaged in various tasks. We had to clear lots of equipment and clean many different spaces around the Oval. I walked from the Clock Building over towards the marquee (a big tent), where there were others gathered waiting for jobs to do. As I approached, I saw that Makayla was standing between me and the others. She saw me walking in her general direction and what she did next was unexpected. Makayla raised her right arm and extended her hand to me, I could tell that she seemed tired and probably needed a boost. But at the same time, I needed to get to where I was going so that we could finish up the work for the day. Then, an idea struck me, I continued to walk her way, slightly to the left of her, but with even greater speed. As I got closer, I raised my right arm as well, grabbed her hand, let go and both of us were propelled in the opposite direction. What a strange story, it all happened in about fifteen seconds. I look at it as a physical example of how our class can work together to be propelled into God’s calling for us, even if we aren’t going in the same direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/hand.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An open hand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As we were cleaning up on Monday after the WISE (Wales, Ireland, Scotland, England) Gathering this past weekend, we were all engaged in various tasks. We had to clear lots of equipment and clean many different spaces around the Oval. I walked from the Clock Building over towards the marquee (a big tent), where there were others gathered waiting for jobs to do. As I approached, I saw that Makayla was standing between me and the others. She saw me walking in her general direction and what she did next was unexpected. Makayla raised her right arm and extended her hand to me, I could tell that she seemed tired and probably needed a boost. But at the same time, I needed to get to where I was going so that we could finish up the work for the day. Then, an idea struck me, I continued to walk her way, slightly to the left of her, but with even greater speed. As I got closer, I raised my right arm as well, grabbed her hand, let go and both of us were propelled in the opposite direction. What a strange story, it all happened in about fifteen seconds. I look at it as a physical example of how our class can work together to be propelled into God’s calling for us, even if we aren’t going in the same direction.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Çocuk Bayramı</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/04/27/cocuk-bayrami.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Çocuk Bayramı" /><published>2018-04-27T16:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-27T16:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/04/27/cocuk-bayrami</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/04/27/cocuk-bayrami.html">&lt;p&gt;Last Sunday, I had the opprotunity to help facilitate a Çocuk Bayramı holiday for a Turkish-speaking church in London. This is a an annual children’s holiday in Turkey to celebrate the people of the future. It has been celebrated in Turkey for about a hundred years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About ten of us from YWAM Harpenden went to the church by car, we set up in the church hall. Much Turkish food had been prepared, which was great to eat and provided lots of interesting tastes. We played games with the kids at first, had a dance competition and then finished with crafts. The craft that I helped with were paper plate face masks, other crafts were flower pots, cupcake decorating and colouring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/children.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Children running&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was a lot of fun and showed me more of what the church is like in London, especially for immigrants. The kids were full of energy and enjoyed the time that is set aside for them. It was also really good to meet with new people and hear their stories. I am really glad that I went and stepped out into something unknown. I hope to go back again sometime soon and continue in serving the Turkish people in London.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Last Sunday, I had the opprotunity to help facilitate a Çocuk Bayramı holiday for a Turkish-speaking church in London. This is a an annual children’s holiday in Turkey to celebrate the people of the future. It has been celebrated in Turkey for about a hundred years now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Biblical Worldview</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/04/27/biblical-worldview.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Biblical Worldview" /><published>2018-04-27T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-27T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/04/27/biblical-worldview</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/04/27/biblical-worldview.html">&lt;p&gt;Our lectures on Monday and Tuesday this week were on Biblical Worldview with Rebekah Hodder. A worldview is a set of assumpitons held consciously or unconsciously in faith about the makeup of the world and how it works. In essence, it is the story we tell to explain the world. There are many worldviews out there but the categories that we focused on were Biblical theism, Animism and secularism/humanism. Before we started looking at the specifics of these worldviews, we learned about how important it is to not just tell others truth, but to really live and share it through actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/child-with-bible.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A child with a Bible&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if we are Christians, it can be possible that we have a partial worldview rooted in something besides the Bible. This is one of the importances of studying worldview, so that we know what we believe and why, to cast off anything that isn’t of God. We walked through four questions and how each worldview would answer them: what are the origins of everything? What is humanity? What is the world? What is our ultimate destiny? It was very helpful to me to hear the different worldviews and understand that biblical truth gives hope and redemption for humanity. We were created intentionally by a Creator God and we are co-laboring with him to bring restoration to all things.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Our lectures on Monday and Tuesday this week were on Biblical Worldview with Rebekah Hodder. A worldview is a set of assumpitons held consciously or unconsciously in faith about the makeup of the world and how it works. In essence, it is the story we tell to explain the world. There are many worldviews out there but the categories that we focused on were Biblical theism, Animism and secularism/humanism. Before we started looking at the specifics of these worldviews, we learned about how important it is to not just tell others truth, but to really live and share it through actions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Soul Keeping?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/04/26/soul-keeping.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Soul Keeping?" /><published>2018-04-26T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-26T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/04/26/soul-keeping</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/book-report/2018/04/26/soul-keeping.html">&lt;p&gt;The book, Soul Keeping, is about how to care for your soul, the innermost part of yourself that is not a part of your body. The author, John Ortberg explains these points in the form of a story of his different stories about Dallas Willard. It begins with information on what the soul is and how it can become polluted. Then, he writes about how to take care of your soul in many ways. The book ends with the story of Dallas Willard’s death and the state of his soul during that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soul Keeping showed me the importance of caring for my inner life and that it will affect everything that I am. I was inspired by a story in the book that told of a man who cared for streams of water that flowed down into a village. Without that care, the village became sick from poluted waters. The village represents all of myself and the water flowing down represents my soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also inspired by me showing the difference between being busy and hurried. Being busy isn’t bad by itself, it can point me to God for strength. Being hurried however keeps me focusing on myself and drains me spiritually. The hurried mentality also keeps me from focusing on what I am doing and instead I am preoccupied by other things on my mind. Solitude can provide rest for the soul, I appreciated this, “Solitude provides shelter from noise and distraction, and that can be scary. We have become almost addicted to both.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciated the part where John Ortberg talks about the soul’s need of a centre, meaning a purpose. We can get easily caught up in what we do and how we do it, but why do we do things? Without a clear centre in my life, I will become impatitent and easily lost. Through focusing on the why, I can be more confident in daily decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was challenged by the writings about keeping your soul close to God, to draw from his strength and his words. If I intentionally choose to be in the presence of God, my soul will be in a good place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I appreciated being introduced to the life of Dallas Willard through this book, I did not know of him previously. I may read one of his books one day now, he seems like a very wise man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this book was quite difficult to read, I failed to connect with it on a deeper level. I’m not quite sure why this is, it may be that I wasn’t really hearing the author’s stories as much as his quotes of Dallas Willard or others. The author’s stories of Dallas Willard aren’t very detailed and seem to be only there to get to the conversations they had. I view this book as partially a biography of Dallas Willard which is somewhat interesting in its way. For me, I walk away from this book with a renewed calling to live a life that cares for my soul, but in a very academic way, not personal. I’m not saying that it is bad, just that I failed to connect with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While reading the book, I thought about other similar books that I had connected deeply with and what the differences might be that I connected with them and not this one. I think that I can really connect to books that emphasise good storytelling and some explaination with encouragement for practical steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my ministries I am reminded to make sure that my soul is taken care of, but in my opinion the book is inner-focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I have been quite critical, I do believe that I am better off having read the book Soul Keeping, rather than not reading it at all. What is the soul you may ask? I don’t know if I can answer that question in a detailed, accurate way. What I can tell you is that the soul is who you are, not your body, and it requires your upmost care. Entrust your soul to Father God and allow him to continue his work, “(Jesus) forever made perfect those who are being made holy.”, Hebrews 10:14.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The book, Soul Keeping, is about how to care for your soul, the innermost part of yourself that is not a part of your body. The author, John Ortberg explains these points in the form of a story of his different stories about Dallas Willard. It begins with information on what the soul is and how it can become polluted. Then, he writes about how to take care of your soul in many ways. The book ends with the story of Dallas Willard’s death and the state of his soul during that time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spiritual Formation?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/04/23/spiritual-formation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spiritual Formation?" /><published>2018-04-23T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-23T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/04/23/spiritual-formation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/lectures/2018/04/23/spiritual-formation.html">&lt;p&gt;Our first week of lectures on the School of Ministry Development was Emmanuel Entee teaching on spiritual formation, but what does that even mean? Spiritual formation is simply becoming more and more of a reflection on Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first day we looked at the spiritual formation of Samuel in the Bible. Samuel grew up in a context of people who did not know God closely at all and were indifferent to him. Yet, he was formed by the intimate time he spent with God, his humility and his service to others. As he grew into a leader, people knew him for being authentic and credible, “He is held in high honor by all the people because everything he says comes true.” - 1 Samuel 9:6. We also see throughout Samuel’s life that he was fully engaged in the society around him, he was not a guru that was distant from the world, he stayed relevant. His legacy from his spiritual formation is that he realigned the nation to godly values, influenced the country’s power structures (King Saul and David) and led in hearing the voice of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the week we talked about different spiritual disciplines to grow in our intimacy with God. A few examples are prayer, silence before God, journaling, studying the Bible and more. Lastly, Emmanuel taught on guidance and being resilient. This part impacted me the most, especially in three points to be attentive to when processing through guidance form the Lord. Be rooted in the unchanging nature of God and his Word when taking steps. Process through guidance in community of brothers and sisters in Christ. Reflect God’s caring nature in following guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/reflection.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A reflection of a tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continue in my walk with God, I will be open and vulnerable to him to allow him to work in my life and make me a better reflection of Christ each day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Our first week of lectures on the School of Ministry Development was Emmanuel Entee teaching on spiritual formation, but what does that even mean? Spiritual formation is simply becoming more and more of a reflection on Jesus Christ.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Bountiful Brunch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/04/23/a-bountiful-brunch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Bountiful Brunch" /><published>2018-04-23T07:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-04-23T07:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/04/23/a-bountiful-brunch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/somd/life/2018/04/23/a-bountiful-brunch.html">&lt;p&gt;Here at YWAM Harpenden, staff and students live in several buildings around the campus. We do life together; working, eating, studying and having fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Karen, a fellow staff member, invited me to brunch. Two others from the School of Ministry Development went as well as many from around the base. Wow, there was a lot of food, Karen is American and the selection reflected that. There was bacon, eggs, fruit, cookies, blueberries, cobbler, coffee and juice. We talked a little about new life, blueberries and breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy these times very much and in different ways. It is fun to be around friends and enjoy a meal together, we laugh quite a lot in these times. These times of being together is relaxing, especially after a long week. It is good to slow down after a week of being busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A deeper experience is that I feel closer to God when I am around other brothers and sisters in these times. I can see more of him when I can see him in the lives of believers. We have been learning this week about the importance of community in developing our spiritual foundation. The early church lived this out each day, they knew that they needed one another. “No one has ever seen God. But if we love each other, God lives in us, and his love is brought to full expression in us.” - 1 John 4:12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see the Father’s face even more clearly, get to know a brother while eating bacon together.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/bacon-and-eggs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bacon and eggs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Here at YWAM Harpenden, staff and students live in several buildings around the campus. We do life together; working, eating, studying and having fun.</summary></entry></feed>